gossipcop.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy | Gossip Cop

### This Privacy Statement Covers Gossip Cop Media – UPDATED May, 25, 2018

Thank you for visiting GossipCop.com. We have updated our Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use, disclose and otherwise treat your personal data, be it in the United States or elsewhere in North America, South America, Europe, Asia, Africa, Australia, and Antarctica.

 **Information Collection**

Gossip Cop Media may collect information from our users at different points on the site. The collection is done via the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our website. From that we theoretically garner information about your computer, mobile device, tablet, web browser and operating system and their settings, as well as the referring page that directed you to GossipCop.com through a link, content or ads you see or click on during a visit. We also could collect information about when you visited, the duration, searches you may have done on the site, and if you left to go to another website. Often sites use this information to monitor their services and tailor content based on your information. In reality, GossipCop.com does not do that since our content is contingent on fact-checking reports by other outlets.

 **Newsletters**

Gossip Cop Media offers e-mail newsletters. Users who subscribe to the Gossip Cop Media newsletter will receive regular email updates about new content and features. To sign up to receive regular e-mails, users must submit information including a valid e-mail address. Gossip Cop Media does not share contact or personal information with any other organization. Users who choose to sign up for a mailing list will receive regular e-mails, including new articles added to the site.  You can choose not to receive such messages in the future by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.

 **Cookies**

Gossip Cop Media may use cookies. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer or other device, tied to information about the user. We may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. Session ID cookies terminate as soon as the user closes his or her browser. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help instructions. For individuals in Europe to learn more about how cookies in the EU, please visit the Cookie Policy linked to the EU-based Service you are using.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies. One can set one’s browser option so that you won’t receive cookies and can also delete existing cookies from your browser. However, the site might not function properly if you’ve refused cookies or similar tracking technologies. Please be aware that disabling cookies or similar tracking technologies might prevent you from accessing some of our content. If you wish to block cookies, go to http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ to find out how, or check your browser’s instructions.

 **Third-Party Cookies**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads and collect information when you visit Gossip Cop. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Third-party advertisers’ use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies. Gossip Cop has no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, go to networkadvertising.org/choices

 **Log Files**

Like most websites, our servers use log files. These log files record include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. Gossip Cop Media uses this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. Gossip Cop Media may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement, though it has never done so to date from its inception in July 2009.

 **Legal Disclaimer**

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, Gossip Cop Media may need to disclose personal information when required by law, wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process.

 **Business Transitions**

In the event Gossip Cop Media goes through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, sale of a portion of its assets, or dissolution such as a bankruptcy or wind down of business, users’ personal information may be part of the assets transferred.

 **Third-Party Websites And Social Media**

Gossip Cop Media publishes articles with links to other sites. It should be noted that our linking does not mean an endorsement of the entity. Please be aware that Gossip Cop Media is not responsible for the practices or content of such other sites and that they have their own privacy policies. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Gossip Cop Media.

Articles on this site may include embedded content, such as videos and images. Similarly, that content is governed by the website or other entity. It may collect data about you, use cookies, embed third-party tracking, and observe your interaction with that content.

Various social network and sharing tools are available on the site, but they are operated by third parties, often employing a “share” button. When visiting a page with one of these sharing tools, the third-party company that operates the tool may be collecting information about your online activity, browser and device from its own tracking technologies. They, of course, are unrelated to Gossip Cop Media and have their own privacy policies.

 **Third-Party Advertising**

The advertisements appearing on this website and on mobile are delivered to users by Google, among other services. Information about a user’s visit to GossipCop.com, such as the number of times they have viewed an advertisement (but not username, date of birth, or any other personal information), is used to serve ads to users on this site. Some of our third-party advertisers may use cookies on our site. Gossip Cop Media has no access to or control over these cookies once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Gossip Cop Media only, and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

The third-party advertising we use, including Google also subscribe to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Principles and/or are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). For additional information about data collection practices of NAI members, as well as your options to opt out, please visit the NAI’s website (http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). For more information on EU online choices, please visit the EU online choices website (http://www.youronlinechoices.com). And you can opt out of Google’s advertising by visiting the About Google Ads page (https://support.google.com/adsense/troubleshooter/1631343?hl=en).

 **Information Collected Through Third-Party Sources**

This type of information is collected anonymously by approved third-party partners (such as social media companies, ad targeting firms, and other partners). None of the information collected by these sources contains any personally identifying information. This type of information includes but is not limited to:

*Demographic information (gender, age, HHI, job title, interests, etc.)  
*Advertising information (clicks, interactions, post-impression performance data)  
*Social networking information (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.)  
*Research information (data collected from partners)

 **Data Breach Procedures We Have In Place**

Gossip Cop Media has implemented state-of-the-art technical and physical security measures to protect the security of any personal information we collect. We constantly upgrade and maintain these safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, disclosure, and any other type of unlawful processing of personal data obtained by us. And we employ service providers who are held to a similar high standard for safety and security. Unfortunately, in these days, even the biggest Internet companies are not 100 percent impervious. While we continue to do the best to protect your personal information, since there is alway a potential risk, one should only access services in secure environments.

 **Notification of Changes**

Whenever Gossip Cop Media changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate.

 **Contact Information**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact info@GossipCop.com.
